okay so we have our VL IW backward
compatibility quiz let's work on a
solution we had a simple VL IW that had
64 bit instructions and we were doing
one one of those at a time and each of
those were equivalent to two normal
operations now we want to have a viola W
processor with four operations per cycle
and the way we want to do that while
maintaining backward compatibility with
the original version is to fetch the
code and execute two of those 64-bit
instructions per cycle the question is
is this new processor hey viola W
processor the correct answer here is no
not really
here's why in a real viola W processor
the compiler tells us which operations
can be done in parallel by putting them
in the same instruction and then we try
to do only one of those instructions per
cycle does every cycle we are guaranteed
that we are doing independent operations
when we run programs compiled for this
processor the compiler only guarantees
that the two operations in the same
instruction are in parallel in fact if
we have something like this where we
have a data dependence the compiler will
put these operations into two separate
viola W instructions and put no ops for
the second operation to ensure that we
first do this and then we do this if
this processor now is trying to fetch
decode and execute to such 64-bit
instructions per cycle it might easily
fetch this too and try to do them in the
same cycle thus violating this
dependence so this type of processor is
not a true viola W processor because it
would have to check for dependencies
which makes it similar to a normal
superscalar processor